CHRISTOPHER JOHNSON

Software Developer

PERSONAL PROFILE

I served my nation as a medic in the US Army for 8 years. My experience in the Army helped me develop complex problem solving, teamwork, and leadership skills. I am looking forward to continuing a career in software development to further these skills. I also enjoy working as part of a team and being a vital member of an organization's culture.

PROJECTS

Revolving Art | Individual

Revolving Art is an app that allows artists to connect with local businesses and have their art featured.

- -Used wireframing and ERD's
- -Front-end Capstone built using React.js, reactstrap, JS, CSS, and external API's
- -Object-oriented programming

Nutshell | Group

Nutshell is a social app that allows users to interact with other users. I worked with three other team members, and my contributions were the news articles, navbar, and logo design.

- -Used github projects to create tickets
- Had daily standup meetings to report progress

GET IN TOUCH

Mobile: 256-701-7935

Email: christopherjohnson1@gmail.com <u>LinkedIn</u>: linkedin.com/in/christopher-johnson1/

<u>Github</u>: github.com/christopherjohnson1 Personal site: www.chrisjdev.com

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Software Developer | Jan 2020 - PRESENT

Nashville Software School

Intensive full-time 6-month software development bootcamp where material comprehension was achieved with individual and group projects.

Tech stack: Python, Django, SQL, React.js, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3

- Developed full CRUD functional apps using github for version control, and all of the languages from the tech stack to deliver full-stack product
- Used Slack and Zoom for all communications
- Worked in agile work environment with daily standups
- Experience working on team and individual projects

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Painter | visual arts

Personal art studio 2015 - PRESENT

- Created acrylic on canvas paintings
- Managed social media accounts to generate sales
- · Participated in art shows
- Arranged for art to be displayed with local vendors

Combat Medic

US Army 2006-2014

As a medic in the Army I was responsible for the lives of the Soldiers assigned to my unit. I had two combat deployments, and a humanitarian assistance deployment to Haiti.

- Managed, and developed a team of 10 junior medics
- Advanced EMT instructor
- Proficient with tactical/ trauma medicine
- Tracked the continuing education requirements for my team, and conducted training to cover any areas necessary to maintain currency
- Coordinated with multiple assets using both radio and satellite communications
- Provided emergency life saving interventions during airborne operations
- Had active security clearance, expired 2016

EDUCATION

Full Stack Developer

Nashville Software School 2020-2021